Guide to the Abu Dhabi Film Festival Collection AD.MC.006
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
Abu Dhabi Film Festival Collection
1940-2014
2007-2014
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
AD.MC.006
17
1.5 Linear Feet approximately 150 DVDs
The Abu Dhabi Film Festival Collection includes DVD copies of many films screened over the course of the festival's 2007-2014 run and ephemera related to the festival. The films represent the different sections of each festival as well as the work of local and international filmmakers.
Biographical / Historical
The Abu Dhabi Film Festival began in 2007 as the Middle East International Film Festival, rebranding itself in 2009. Since its inception, the festival's mission has been to foster a "vibrant film culture throughout the region." As part of this aim, ADFF worked to curate "exceptional international programmes to engage and educate the local community, inspire young filmmakers from the region and nurture the growth of the regional film industry." The annual event incorporated a variety of programs into the festival, including film screenings and competitions, galas, talks, workshops, and master classes. As represented by the films in this collection, the festival was international in nature. Many of the films though come from local or regional filmmakers (UAE and GCC) who competed in the festival's Emirates Film Competition. A portion of those filmmakers are amateur, part-time, or novice filmmakers. The festival was closed down after the 2014 iteration, with support for local and regional filmmakers continuing through the Sanad Abu Dhabi Film Fund.
http://www.sanadfilmfund.com/en/Images/ADFF14-guide-English_tcm14-20554.pdf http://www.thenational.ae/uae/abu-dhabi-film-festival-to-be-closed-down
Arrangement
The collection is organized chronologically by festival year. Within each annual version of the festival, the films are organized by the categories and competitions they were presented in at the festival, and within the categories they are organized alphabetically.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains DVD copies of films screened at the Abu Dhabi Film Festival from its first festival in 2007 to the final one in 2014. The films represented in the collection come from the different competitions, showcases, and presentations from each of the versions of the festival; the national, regional, and international films are both documentary and fiction (narrative) in both short and feature length. The collection is made up of works that were made for submission to the festival, or were screened at many film festivals that year, as well as older films that were presented as part of showcases and retrospectives. Along with the films, the collection contains ephemera and publications (guides, brochures) from the festival.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers. For more information contact nyuad-asc-group@nyu.edu.
Custodial History
The films in the collection were acquired from the filmmakers or purchased from various commercial outlets by the NYU Abu Dhabi Library Archives and Special Collections. The accompanying archival material was collected by the library or acquired by donation.
- 2007 Middle East International Film Festival, 370
  - Egg, 2007; 371
  - Kemo Sabe, 2007; 414
- 2008 Middle East International Film Festival, 231
  - Beirut: Open City, 2008; 347
  - Breadmakers, 2007; 276
  - The Brothers Bloom, 2008; 349
  - Cherry Blossoms, 2008; 373
  - Depth Wish, 2007; 360
  - Disgrace, 2008; 375
  - The Dove's Lost Necklace, 1991; 374
  - Dunya & Desie, 2008; 358
  - Easy Virtue, 2008; 348
  - Flow, 2008; 356
  - Football Under Cover, 2008; 357
  - Hipsters, 2008; 355
  - Igor, 2008; 354
  - In Vivid Detail, 2007; 232
  - Karzzzz, 2008; 361
  - Let the Right One In, 2008; 359
  - The Lucky Ones, 2008; 345
  - Man on Wire, 2008; 372
  - Maradona, 2008; 365
  - Middle of Nowhere, 2008; 366
  - Mishima: A Life in Four Chapters, 1985; 351
  - My Olympic Summer, 2008; 317
  - O'Horten, 2007; 367
  - On a Day Like Today, 2008; 209
  - Rumba, 2008; 363
  - Standard Operating Procedure, 2008; 350
  - Stranded, 2007; 343
  - Two-Legged Horse, 2008; 369
  - The Wackness, 2008; 352
  - The Yellow Handkerchief, 2008; 353
  - Youssou N'Dour: I Bring What I Love, 2008; 344
- 2009 Abu Dhabi Film Festival, 200
  - Documentary Competition, 201
    - All My Mothers, 2008; 202 (Disk ADFF 2009-11)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Original Format: Digital Betacam
      Color
      Total Running Time: 00:60:00
      Details:
      Directors: Ebrahim Saeedi, Sahavi Sanjavi (Iran, Iraq)
      Original Title: Hamey-e Madaran-e Man
    - Goodbye, How Are You?, 2009; 272 (Disk ADFF 2009-4)
      Director: Boris Mitic (Serbia)
      Original Title: Dovidjenja, kako ste?
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Goodbye, How Are You?
      More Information
    - On the Way to School, 2008; 376 (Disk ADFF 2009-3)
      Original Format: 35mm
      Total Running Time: 01:21:00
      Directors: Orhan Eskiloy, Ozgur Dogan
      Original Title: Iki Dil Bir Bavul
      Catalog Record: GetIt | On the Way to School
  - Narrative Competition, 226
    - Third Person Singular Number, 2009; 227 (Disk ADFF 2009-9)
      Total Running Time: 02:03:00
      Director: Mostofa Sarwar Farooki (Bangladesh)
      Original Title: Third Person Singular Number
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Third Person Singular Number
  - New Cinema from Turkey, 233
    - Dot, 2009; 234 (Disk ADFF 2009-18)
      Total Running Time: 01:18:00
      Director: Dervis Zaim (Turkey)
      Original Title: Nokta
      Catalog record: GetIt | Dot
    - Milk, 2008; 364 (Disk 2009-19)
      Total Running Time: 01:42:00
      Director: Semih Kaplanoglu
      Original Title: Süt
      Catalog Record: Currently unavailable
  - Shorts Competition, 203
    - Ata, 2008; 323 (Disk ADFF 2009-10)
      Total Running Time: 00:26:00
      Directors: Cagla Zencirci, Guillaume Giovanetti
      Original Title: Ata
      Catalog Record: Get It | Ata
    - Diplomacy, 2009; 308 (Disk ADFF 2009-14)
      Original Format: HDCAM
      Total Running Time: 00:09:00
      Director: Jon Goldman (USA)
      Original Title: Diplomacy
      Catalog Record: Get It| Diplomacy
    - The Employment, 2008; 316 (Disk ADFF 2009-17)
      Total Running Time: 00:06:00
      Director: Santiago 'Bou' Grasso
      Original Title: El Empleo
      Catalog Record: Get It | The Employment
    - Fatenah, 2009; 206 (Disk ADFF 2009-16)
      Originial Format: Digital Betacam
      Total Running Time: 00:30:00
      Director: Ahmad Habash (Palestine)
      Original Title: Fatenah
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Fatenah
    - Glory at Sea, 2008; 274 (Disk ADFF 2009-6)
      Total Running Time: 00:25:00
      Director: Benh Zeitlin (USA)
      Original Title: Glory at Sea
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Glory at Sea
    - Home, 2009; 205 (Disk ADFF 2009-8)
      Director: Matt Faust (USA)
      Original Title: Home
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Home
    - Walls, 2009; 204 (Disk ADFF 2009-7)
      Director: Mohammed Saad Jasim (Iraq)
      Original Title: Walls
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Walls
  - Student Shorts, 212
    - Kasia, 2008; 213 (Disk ADFF 2009-15)
      Total Running Time: 00:10:00
      Director: Elisabet Llado (Belgium)
      Original Title: Kaisa
      Catalog Record: Currently unavaliable
    - Our Neck of the Woods, 2009; 380 (Disk ADFF 2009-2)
      Total Running Time: 00:17:00
      Director: Rob Connolly (USA)
      Original Title: Our Neck of the Woods
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Our Neck of the Woods
    - Schautag, 2008; 273 (Disk ADFF 2009-13)
      Total Running Time: 00:23:00
      Director: Marvin Kren (Germany)
      Original Title: Schautag
      Catalog Record: GetIT | Schautag
    - Surprise, 2008; 377 (Disk ADFF 2009-12)
      Total Running Time: 00:21:00
      Director: Elena Bychkova (Russia)
      Original Title: Surpriz
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Surprise
    - Under Construction, 2009; 283 (Disk ADFF 2009-5)
      Total Running Time: 00:29:00
      Director: Damien Dufresne (France)
      Original Title: Chantier
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Under Construction
  - What in the World are We Doing to our World?, 378
    - The Gift of Pachamama, 2008; 379 (Disk ADFF 2009-1)
      Director: Toshifumi Matsushita
      Original Title: El regalo de la pachamama
      Catalog Record: GetIt |The Gift of Pachamama
- 2010 Abu Dhabi Film Festival, 194
  - Documentary Competition, 211
    - Children of the Stones - Children of the Wall, 2010; 381 (Disk ADFF 2010-2)
      Origial Format: Digital Betacam
      Total Running Time: 01:27:00
      Director: Robert Krieg (Germany)
      Original Title: Kinder der Steine- Kinder der Mauer
    - How Bitter My Sweet!, 2009; 210 (Disk ADFF 2010-12)
      Total Running Time: 01:30:00
      Director: Mohammed Soueid (Lebanon)
      Original Title: Bahebak Ya Wahsh!
      Catalog Record: GetIt | How Bitter My Sweet!
    - Queen of the Sun: What Are the Bees Telling Us?, 2010; 383 (Disk ADFF 2010-14)
      Director: Taggart Siegel (USA)
      Original Title: Queen of the Sun: What Are the Bees Telling Us?
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Queen of the Sun: What Are the Bees Telling Us?
      Total Running Time: 01:22:00
  - Emirates Film Competition, 214
    - Aseel, 2010; 219 (Disk ADFF 2010-17)
      Original Format: MiniDV
      Total Running Time: 00:15:00
      Director: Faisal Al-Harbi (Saudi Arabia)
      Original Title: Aseel
      Catalog Record: Get It | Aseel
    - Father Grant, 2010; 315 (Disk ADFF 2010-20)
      Total Running Time: 00:13:00
      Details
      Director: Ahmed Zain (UAE)
      Original Title: Menhat Al-Waled
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Father Grant
    - Gheamt Shroog, 2010; 313 (Disk ADFF 2010-18)
      Total Running Time: 00:16:00
      Original Title: Gheamt Shroog
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Gheamt Shroog
    - Leap of Faith, 2010; 244 (Disk ADFF 2010-4)
      Director: Amna Ehtesham Khaishgi (UAE)
      Original Title: Qafzat Al-Iman
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Leap of Faith
    - A Sketch of a Life in the UAE, 2010; 215 (Disk ADFF 2009-19)
      Total Running Time: 00:12:00
      Director: Shoko Okurano
      Original Title: Fasel min Al-Hayat
      Catalog Record: GetIt | A Sketch of a Life in the UAE
  - New Horizons Competition, 220
    - The Furious Force of Rhymes, 2010; 302 (Disk ADFF 2010-3)
      Total Running Time: 01:24:00
      Director: Joshua Atesh Litle (USA)
      Arabic, English, French, German, Hebrew, Wolof
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Furious Force of Rhymes
      More Info
    - Living Skin, 2010; 221 (Disk ADFF 2010-15)
      Total Running Time: 00:56:00
      Director: Fawzi Saleh (Egypt)
      Arabic
      Original Title: Jald Hayy
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Living Skin
    - Once Again, 2010; 334 (Disk ADFF 2010-16)
      Total Running Time 01:36:00
      Director: Joud Said (Syria)
      Arabic, French
      Original Title: Marra Oukra
      Catalog Record GetIt | Once Again
    - Sun Dress, 2010; 328 (Disk ADFF 2010-1)
      Original Format: 35 mm
      Director: Saeed Salmeen Al Murry (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Thawb al-Shams
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Sun Dress
  - Short Film Competition, 195
    - Bathing Micky, 2010; 196 (Disk ADFF 2010-6)
      Total Running Time: 00:14:00
      Director: Frida Kempff (Sweden)
      Danish
      Original Title: Micky Bader
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Bathing Micky
    - Formic, 2009; 255 (Disk ADFF 2010-5)
      Total Running Time: 00:04:00
      Director: Roman Kälin, Florian Wittmann (Germany)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Formic
    - In Their Blood, 2009; 270 (Disk ADFF 2010-7)
      Total Running Time: 00:31:00
      Director: Katia Jarjoura (Lebanon, France)
      Original Title: Bi Rouh bi Dam
      Catalog Record: GetIt | In Their Blood
    - La Patrona, 2009; 252 (Disk ADFF 2010-8)
      Total Running Time: 00:05:00
      Director: Lizzette Argüello (Mexico)
      Spanish
      Catalog Record: GetIt | La Patrona
    - Life, 2010; 246 (Disk ADFF 2010-10)
      Total Running Time: 00:18:00
      Director: Walid Tayaa (Tunisia)
      Original Title: El Icha
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Life
    - Muscles, 2009; 245 (Disk ADFF 2010-11)
      Director: Edward Housden (Australia)
      English
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Muscles
    - Under Two Skies, 2010; 225 (Disk 2010-9)
      Director: Zayne Kader Akyol (Canada)
      Turkish, Kurdish, French
      Original Title: İki Bulut Arasında, Sous Deux Ciels
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Unger Two Skies
  - Showcase, 235
    - West is West, 2010; 236 (Disk ADFF 2010-13)
      Director: Andy De Emmony (United Kingdom)
      English, Punjabi
      Catalog Record: GetIt | West Is West
  - What in the World Are We Doing to Our World?, 384
    - Queen of the Sun: What Are the Bees Telling Us?, 2010; 385 (Disk ADFF 2010-14)
      English, Italian
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Queen Of The Sun: What Are The Bees Telling Us
- 2011 Abu Dhabi Film Festival, 197
  - Documentary Feature Competition, 335 (Disk ADFF 2011-1)
    Swedish
    Original Title: Medan du var borta
    Catalog Record: GetIt | While You Were Gone
    - El Gusto, 2011; 336 (Disk ADFF 2011-38)
      Color, Black and White
      Total Running Time: 01:29:00
      Director: Safinez Bousbia (France, Alegeria, Ireland, United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | El Gusto
    - Tahrir 2011: The Good, the Bad, & the Politician, 398 (Disk ADFF 2011-21)
      Original Format: DCP
      Total Running Time: 01:35:00
      Director: Tamer Ezzat, Ayten Amin, Amr Salama (Egypt, United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Al Tayib wa al Shariss wa al Siyassi
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Tahrir 2011: The Good, The Bad, The Politician
  - Emirates Film Competition, 223
    - Darkness, 2011; 338 (Disk ADFF 2011-34)
      Director: Ahmed Zain (United Arab Emirates
      Original Title: Atma
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Darkness
    - Halfway, 2011; 393 (Disk ADFF 2011-33)
      Director: Mohammed Mamdouh (United Arab Emirates)
      Arabic, English
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Halfway
    - Igrab, 2011; 404 (Disk ADFF 2011-37)
      Total Running Time: 00:20:00
      Director: Hamad Saghran (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Igrab
    - Kingdom of Women, 2011; 395 (Disk ADFF 2011-8)
      Director: Amna Ehtesham Khaishgi (Pakistan)
      Urdu
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Kingdom Of Women
    - Lahjatna (Our Accent), 2011; 269 (Disk ADFF 2011-9)
      Director: Mariam Al Nuaimi (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Lahjatna (Our Accent)
    - Layers, 2011; 3459 (Disk ADFF 2011-10)
      Total Running Time: 00:07:00
      Director: Manal Wicki (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Layers
    - Mad Camel, 2011; 318 (Disk ADFF 2011-20)
      Director: Mohammad Fikree (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Mad Camel
    - A Night to Remember, 2011; 399 (Disk ADFF 2011-32)
      Director: Fahmi Farahat (Saudi Arabia)
      Original Title: Laylat Omr
      Catalog Record: GetIt | A Night To Remember
    - Photon, 2011; 325 (Disk ADFF 2011-19)
      Director: Awadh Al Hamzani (Saudi Arabia)
      Arabic, English, Swedish
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Photon
    - Sa'eed, 2011; 394 (Disk ADFF 2011-31)
      Total Running Time: 00:02:00
      Director: Marwan Al Hammadi (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Sa'eed
    - Sons of the Sun, 2010; 312 (Disk ADFF 2011-24)
      Total Running Time: 00:35:00
      Director: Ahmed Abdelnasser (Qatar)
      Catlog Record: GetIt | Sons Of The Sun
    - Soul, 2011; 396 (Disk ADFF 2011-36)
      Director: Fatma Abdullah (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Soul
    - Swing, 2011; 254 (Disk ADFF 2011-30)
      Director: Abdullah Al Daihani (Kuwait)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Swing
    - Telephoni, 2011; 224 (Disk ADFF 2011-29)
      Total Running Time: 00:08:00
      Director: Hassan Kiyany (United Arab Emirates)
      Arabic, Hindi
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Telephoni
  - Narrative Feature Competition, 305
    - Death for Sale, 2011; 306
      Total Running Time: 01:57:00
      Director: Faouzi Bensaïdi (Morocco, France, Belgium, United Arab Emirate)
      Original Title: Baya Al Maut
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Death For Sale
  - New Horizons, 390
    - The End, 2011; 391 (Disk ADFF 2011-23)
      Black and White
      Total Running Time: 01:45:00
      Director: Hicham Lasri (Morocco)
      Original Title: Al Nihaya
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The End
    - Tears of Sand (a.k.a. Wilaya), 2011; 400 (Disk ADFF 2011-3)
      Director: Pedro Pérez Rosado (Spain)
      Hassaniya, Spanish
      Original Title: Lagrimas De Arena
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Wilaya
  - Short Film Competition, 198
    - Bandage, 2011; 303 (Disk ADFF 2011-22)
      Director: Omid Abdollahi (Iran)
      Original Title: Panseman
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Bandage
    - The Barbarians, 2010; 362 (Disk ADFF 2011-27)
      Director: Jean-Gabriel Périot (France)
      Original Title: Les Barbares
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Barbarians
    - Bear, 2011; 401 (Disk ADFF 2011-25)
      Total Running Time: 00:11:00
      Director: Nash Edgerton (Australia)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Bear
    - Blind Date, 2010; 388 (Disk ADFF 2011-14)
      Total Running Time: 00:03:00
      Director: Nigel Davies (United Kingdom)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Blind Date
    - Blue Rinse, 2011; 386 (Disk ADFF 2011-13)
      Director: Matt Leigh (Ireland)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Blue Rinse
    - Deaf Day, 2011; 368 (Disk ADFF 2011-2)
      Director: Rana Kazkaz, Anas Khalaf (Syria)
      Arabic Sign Language
      Original Title: Yom Samt
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Deaf Day
    - Displaced Lives, 2010; 307 (Disk ADFF 2011-4)
      Director: Joăo Marcelo Gomes (Brazil)
      Arabic, Portuguese
      Original Title: Vidas Deslocadas
      Catalog Record:
    - Farewell Exile, 2011; 392 (Disk ADFF 2011-18)
      Director: Lamia Alami (Morocco)
      Original Title: Salam Ghourba
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Farewell Exile
    - Flower Seller, 2010; 298 (Disk ADFF 2011-28)
      Director: Ihab Jadallah (Palestine)
      Original Title: Baya'a El Ward
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Flower Seller
    - Hinterland, 2010; 382 (Disk ADFF (2011-11))
      Director: Jakob Weyde, Jost Althoff (Germany)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Hinterland
    - Luminaris, 2011; 402 (Disk ADFF 2011-26)
      Director: Juan Pablo Zaramella (Argentina)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Luminaris
    - Mkhobbi fi Kobba (Soubresauts), 2011; 230 (Disk ADFF 2011-5)
      Total Running Time: 00:22:00
      Director: Leyla Bouzid (Tunisia, France)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Mkhobbi fi Kobba (Soubresauts)
    - Noise, 2011; 337 (Disk ADFF 2011-6)
      Director: Neeraj Ghaywan (India)
      Hindi
      Original Title: Shor
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Noise
    - Out of Erasers, 2011; 403 (Disk ADFF 2011-16)
      Director: Erik Rosenlund (Denmark, Sweden)
      Original Title: Sudd
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Out Of Erasers
    - Short Memory, 2010; 389 (Disk ADFF 2011-15)
      Director: Marwan Khneisser (Lebanon)
      Original Title: Zakira Kassira
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Shorty Memory
    - Something Left, Something Taken, 2010; 387 (Disk ADFF 2011-12)
      Director: Ru Kuwahata, Max Porter (USA)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Something Left, Something Taken
    - Soul, 2011; 397 (Disk ADFF 2011-36)
    - Specky Four-Eyes, 2010; 309 (Disk ADFF 2011-7)
      Director: Jean-Claude Rozec (France)
      French
      Original Title: Cul de bouteille
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Specky Four-Eyes
    - The Wedding Tape, 2011; 222 (Disk ADFF 2011-17)
      Director: Ariel Shaban (Kosovo, Germany)
      Albanian
      Original Title: Kaseta e Dasmes
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Wedding Tape
    - The Well, 2011; 271 (Disk ADFF 2011-35)
      Arabic, Hebrew
      Original Title: Al Beeer
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Well
    - While You Were Gone (Medan du var borta), 2011; 199
- 2012 Abu Dhabi Film Festival, 216
  - Documentary Competition, 2012; 249
    - Approved for Adoption, 2012; 3248 (Disk ADFF 2012-24)
      Total Running Time: 01:15:00
      Director: Jung Henin, Laurent Boileau (Belgium, France)
      Original Title: Couleur de peau: Miel
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Approved For Adoption
    - Cursed Be the Phosphate, 2012; 250 (Disk ADFF 2012-40)
      Director: Sami Tlili (Lebanon, Qatar, Tunisia, United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Yel'an Bu Al-phosphate
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Cursed Be The Phosphate
    - The House I Live In, 2012; 3253 (Disk ADFF 2012-29)
      Total Running Time: 1:46:00
      Director: Eugene Jarecki (USA)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The House I Live In
    - The List, 2012; 296 (Disk ADFF 2012-48)
      Director: Beth Murphy (USA)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The List
    - Mohammad Saved from the Waters, 2010; 297 (Disk ADFF 2012-54)
      Director: Safaa Fathy (Egypt, France, United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Mohammad sauvé des eaux
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Mohammad Saved From The Waters
    - Stories We Tell, 2012; 3232 (Disk ADFF 2012-5)
      Total Running Time: 01:48:00
      Director: Sarah Polley (Canada)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Stories We Tell
  - Emirates Film Competition, 242
    - Cats, 2012; 339 (Disk ADFF 2012-56)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Cats
    - Children, 2012; 319 (Disk ADFF 2012-41)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Children
    - The Final Division, 2012; 285 (Disk ADFF 2012-42)
      Director: Hana Kazim (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Final Division
    - Foresight, 2011; 330 (Disk ADFF 2012-59)
      Total Running Time: 00:33:00
      Director: Ahmed Zain, Naser Al Yagobi (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Baseera
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Foresight
    - Frozen Yogurt, 2012; 314 (Disk ADFF 2012-60)
      Director: Ahmed Zain (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Laban Mothallaj
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Frozen Yogurt
    - The Gamboo3a Revolution, 2012; 3249 (Disk ADFF 2012-25)
      Deatils:
      Director: Abdulrahman Al Madani (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Gamboo3a Revolution
    - The Journey, 2012; 263 (Disk ADFF 2012-55)
      Director: Hana Makki (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Journey
    - Murk Light, 2012; 327 (Disk ADFF 2012-12)
      Director: Yassir Al Yassiri (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Titlw: Daw' Daames
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Murk Light
    - The Orphanage, 2012; 261 (Disk ADFF 2012-58)
      Director: Mohammed Al Otaiba (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Orphanage
    - Ostora, 2012; 243 (Disk ADFF 2012-11)
      Director: Hani Kichi (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Ostora
    - Patience Salt, 2012; 295 (Disk ADFF 2012-47)
      Director: Mohammed Ibrahim (Bahrain)
      Original Title: Sabr Al Melh
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Patience Salt
    - Smaller than the Sky, 2012; 258 (Disk ADFF 2012-57)
      Director: Abdulla Hassan Ahmed (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Smaller Than The Sky
    - Three Dolls and a Paper Plane, 2012; 3237 (Disk ADFF 2012-14)
      Director: Hend Al Fahad (Saudi Arabia)
      Original Title: Thalath 'Araaes W Taaera Waraqeiya
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Three Dolls And A Paper Plane
  - Narrative Competition, 3238
    - Ginger and Rosa, 2012; 3244 (Disk ADFF 2012-20)
      Director: Sally Potter (United Kingdom, Canada, Croatia, Denmark)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Ginger And Rosa
    - Lore, 2012; 3239 (Disk ADFF 2012-15)
      Director: Cate Shortland (Germany, Australia, United Kingdom)
      German
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Lore